<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FAIRDataPipeline</title>
    <link>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content on FAIRDataPipeline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/standard_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/standard_api/</guid>
      <description>Standardised data type API # Unless otherwise specified this document uses the “current” metadata scheme defined in the &amp;ldquo;Metadata and data representation” document. You do not need to have read that document to be able to read and understand (the majority of) this one.
The standardised data type API is defined more in terms of file formats than it is in terms of data types. There are two file formats: parameter files, and hdf5 files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/file_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/file_api/</guid>
      <description>File API # The file API manages file access, provenance, and metadata # The API is accessed as a &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo;. All reads and writes are recorded and logged into a file when the session closes. Files are identified by their metadata, though the metadata is handled differently for reads (where the files are expected to exist) and writes (where they typically do not), described in more detail below.
The file API behaviour is entirely determined by a yaml configuration file (referred to here as a “config.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminology</title>
      <link>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.fairdatapipeline.org/docs/API/python/terminology/</guid>
      <description>Terminology used in this document # datum A specific value, encoded in a particular way, that travels through the data pipeline. config.yaml A file (potentially with a different name) used by the data pipeline to allow users to override default pipeline behaviour. See the File API specification for more details. metadata.yaml A file used by the data pipeline to describe available data files, listing their associated metadata. See the File API specification for more details.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
